worldmathday.com 2014-11-24

# 3P Learning Privacy Policy

##### 

##### ****

### About 3P Learning

  * 3P Learning is a global e-learning resource company. We produce a range of online resources and a network of websites including but not limited to those for the [Mathletics](http://www.mathletics.com/ "Mathletics"), [Spellodrome](http://www.spellodrome.com/ "Spellodrome"), [Reading Eggs](http://www.readingeggs.com/ "Reading Eggs"), [IntoScience](http://www.intoscience.com/ "IntoScience") and [World Education Games](http://www.worldeducationgames.com/ "World Education Games") brands.
  * Each resource operates under the 3P Learning brand, together with challenge websites for national and regional events which may use or integrate with some of the aforementioned websites (the Site) are owned and operated by 3P Learning Pty Ltd (3P Learning).
  * References to the Site in this Privacy Policy document include all related 3P Learning brand websites, as mentioned above. This document refers to all contact with the 3P Learning resources, via online access of range of mobile applications available.

### About 3P Learning’s Privacy Policy

  *  3P Learning is committed to protecting the safety and security of our registered users ( **Registrants** ) and are sensitive to our Registrant’s concerns about the safety of the personal information provided to us. **Please read this Privacy Policy carefully in order to understand how any personal information collected by us is used.**
  * Registrants must agree to their personal information being used by 3P Learning in accordance with this Privacy Policy before they may register.
  * This Privacy Statement has been developed in accordance with…

.

  * ___The Australian Privacy Amendment (Enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012_
  * ___The Australian Privacy Regulation 2013_
  * ___The United Kingdom Privacy Protection Act 1998_
  * ___The United States Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and Rule as administered by the Federal Trade Commission_
  * ___The United States Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act_
  * ___The Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act_
  * ___The Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA)_

#### ****

### General Communication Principle

The Site does not provide students with any means to communicate directly with each other. There are no chat rooms connected with the learning resources. At all times, students are engaged in meaningful educative activity within a secure environment.

### What personal information we collect

  * In order to register for 3P Learning resources, students registering individually and not part of a school, must give their consent (or if they are under 13 years of age a parent or guardian must consent on their behalf) at the time of registration to provide us with their name, age, and their email address. Alternatively, parents registering on behalf of their child(ren), must give their consent at the time of registration to provide us with their own name, and email address, and the name(s) and age(s) of their child(ren).
  * Teachers registering for their class or school must give their consent at the time of registration to provide us with their own name, class name, school name and their email address. In addition, teachers must consent for their students to participate at the time of registration and provide us with the names of their students.
  * Registrants who do not give this consent cannot provide us with their personal information or the names of the students and cannot use the Site.
  * We require this information in order to correctly identify each Registrant as a Site user, manage their account and for certain other purposes detailed below.

### What we will do with your information

The information collected from Registrants is used for the following purposes:

  * to send a confirmation notice to the Registrant of the registration;
  * upon the Registrant’s request, to reset a password for a lost or forgotten password;
  *  to respond to any questions, concerns or problems raised by the Registrant;
  * to contact the Registrant about any problems with the Registrant’s account or conduct on the Site;
  * to send out a 3P Learning newsletter or emails about the Site;
  * to publish the names of winners and high performers on the Site or in the 3P Learning newsletter and to provide all the results data for each Registrant;
  * to send prizes or certificates for participation and performance on the Site.

3P Learning is unique in the sense that there are numerous special events that keep the Site constantly fresh, challenging, fun and interesting for our Registrants.

We use the 3P Learning product newsletters or emails to notify our users of all the current events, changes, improvements, upgrades, rules, and so on, of the Site. In addition, we may notify our Registrants of new products and services that 3P Learning has designed and made available to the Registrants. In all communications, Registrants may opt out at any time by following the specific opt out instructions within the communications that we send.

### What we will not do with your personal information

3P Learning will keep your personal information confidential and not sell or knowingly divulge your information to advertisers or any external third parties, unless:

  * we are required to share your information with a third party in order to comply with law or to comply with a court order or subpoena;
  * to enforce our website or event rules; or
  * to protect the safety and security of our Registrants and our Site.

Generally we will only use your information within 3P Learning. However, sometimes we provide data on results to government education departments, peak bodies managing or representing schools, or schools themselves. We will require these third parties to comply strictly with our instructions and we will require that they do not have access to your personal information and not use the data for commercial purposes.

### How we process your information

We ask for Registrants’ consent to the use of any personal information we collect from them in accordance with our Privacy Policy at the time of registration. If a Registrant does not wish to provide us with their consent, they cannot agree to the Site Terms and Conditions and must not use the Site.

Our use of the personal information we collect is necessary in order for us to maintain the Site and facilitate Registrants’ use of the Site. We do not collect any unnecessary personal data from Registrants (for instance, their race or religious beliefs).

### How long we hold your information

We will keep any personal information we collect from Registrants for as long as they are registered users of the Site. If a Registrant cancels their registration or it otherwise lapses after 3 years of not using the Site, we will only keep their personal information for the purposes of sending the Registrant information regarding 3P Learning’s other products and services if they agree to receive this information. Personal information is otherwise deleted or destroyed.

### Keeping your personal information accurate

The personal information we hold about a Registrant (such as their name, address and school) is kept so that we may correctly identify that Registrant. Registrants can update their personal information at anytime by contacting 3P Learning (details below).

### Keeping your personal information secure

3P Learning is committed to information security. We will use all reasonable endeavours to keep Registrants’ personal information in a secure environment. For instance, each Registrant’s personal information is encrypted whilst being sent to our server at the time of registration. However, security cannot be guaranteed due to the nature of the internet.

3P Learning’s security measures are designed to assist in Registrants’ personal information not being accessed by unauthorised personnel, lost or misused. If you reasonably believe that there has been an unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal information please let us know by contacting our Privacy and Data Protection Officer (contact details below).

### Anonymous information

In addition to personal information and results data, 3P Learning also collects anonymous information about Registrants and the activities of Registrants on the Site. Anonymous information is information that is not linked to the name of a user. This information is used to assist us in enhancing the learning resources and the information remains anonymous at all times.

When agreeing to the Site Terms and Conditions, Registrants grant 3P Learning the right to use this anonymous information for its own purposes, such as the preparation of statistical reports, provided 3P Learning otherwise complies with its obligations in respect of the use of personal information.

### Revision of Privacy Policy

3P Learning reserves the right to change, modify, or revise this Privacy Policy in order to comply with any applicable laws or for any other reason at any time. Therefore our Registrants are required to check the Privacy Policy periodically to read about any changes, modifications, or revisions. Registrants may wish to check it each time they submit personal information. You will be deemed to have consented to such variation by your continued use of the Site following any changes being made.

### How can parents access, change or delete personally identifiable information about their child?

Registrants have a right to get a copy from us of the personal information we hold about them. If you wish to receive a copy of this information please address your request to the Privacy and Data Protection Officer (contact details below). We will deal with your request promptly and in any case at least within 45 days of the date of receiving it. We will correct or delete inaccurate or incomplete personal information we hold about you at your request.

### Public Displays of Names

3P Learning strives to provide highly engaging websites for students. Given students have indicated their strong preference for their name to be shown publicly, in recognition of their achievements, we allow this – but we do not allow full names (ie First Name and Surname) to be shown publicly.

**All administrative user access to any 3P Learning Site permits the full anonymising of names, where preferred by the user.**

### Cookies

A cookie is a little piece of information handed to a web browser from a web server that contains information that can be retrieved from the server later. When you visit the Site the server may attach a cookie to your computer’s memory. 3P Learning uses cookies only to the limited extent to recognise the Registrant when they visit the Site and pairing that Registrant with the account (and account preferences) that the Registrant created. However, this information is not linked to any personal information that Registrant may provide and cannot be used to identify Registrants. You should be able to configure your computer so that it disables cookies.

To help us better understand you needs and better share content, we also use analytical software. This software will save a cookie to your computers hard drive in order to track and monitor your engagement and usage of the website but will not store, save or collect personal information. You can read Google’s privacy policy here for further information [ <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>[ ](http://www.google.com/privacy.html)].

Other cookies may be stored to your computers hard drive when this website uses referral programs, sponsored links or adverts – which is extremely rare. Such cookies typically expire after 30 days, though some may take longer. No personal information is stored, saved or collected without your consent.

### Transfer of your data

Registrants’ personal information is uploaded to and kept on servers that we maintain or that are maintained by third parties that comply with strict contractual privacy obligations. It is not otherwise transferred internationally except where a copy is sent to the Registrant itself at their request. Registrants must consent for their personal information to be transferred and stored in this manner at the time of registration.

### Special Notice To Parents

3P Learning has no intention of seeking personal information about minors who visit our Web Sites. If such information is collected, this Privacy Statement will apply to that information. In addition, if we can identify a user as a minor, the personal information will not be used for further marketing and promotion unless the minor’s guardian has consented. We encourage you to ask your children to seek your permission before providing information about themselves or their family over the Internet.

### Special Notice To Children

Ask your parent or guardian for permission before you send any personal information over the Internet, including to our Web Sites.

### More Privacy Information

For more information on privacy legislation and guidelines in your local jurisdiction please contact your relevant local authorities.

  * __**Australia:**  [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/ "Australia")
  * __**Canada:**  [www.privcom.gc.ca](http://www.privcom.gc.ca/ "Canada")
  * __**European Union:**  <http://ec.europa.eu/justice_home/fsj/privacy/>
  * __**India:**  <http://www.mit.gov.in/default.aspx>
  * __**New Zealand:**  [www.privacy.org.nz](http://www.privacy.org.nz/ "New Zealand")
  * __**Singapore:**  [www.mica.gov.sg](http://www.mica.gov.sg/ "Singapore")
  * __**United Kingdom:**   [www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/ "UK")
  * __**USA:**  [www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/ "USA")

### 

### Special Notice For Users in Canada

3P Learning is fully committed to providing access to our resources through an environment that is fully compliant with all national and provincial privacy requirements for our users across Canada. This Privacy Policy has been developed with the standards required to be compliant with the Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act and the Canadian Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA).

We sometimes transfer personal information to others, including to affiliated entities or unrelated companies (“service providers”), that carry out certain functions on our behalf such as order fulfillment, accounts receivable and data processing. In those cases we require those service providers not to use or disclose your personal information for any purpose other than as directed by 3P Learning. Some of these service providers may be located outside of Canada, including in the United States, and your personal information may be collected, used, disclosed, stored and processed in those jurisdictions for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement.

We take all reasonable contractual or other measures to protect your personal information while processed or handled by these service providers. If your personal information is located outside Canada it will be subject to legal requirements in those foreign countries applicable to our service providers, for example, lawful requirements to disclose personal information to government authorities in those countries.

#### 

### Contacting 3P Learning about this Privacy Policy

#### Please address all requests and questions about this Privacy Policy to the **Privacy and Data Protection Officer**  using the email address below.

#### [customerservice@3plearning.com](mailto:customerservice@3plearning.com)
